

Shrikanth Achar **UI UX Designer**

ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate UI/UX designer with 13 yrs of experience. I evaluate UI/UX with my frontend coding skills. My passion for art results in visually stunning and intuitive UX designs. Let's collaborate to create meaningful digital experiences that leave a lasting impact.

EXPERIENCE

Infosys 09, 2016 - Present Sr. Lead UX Design

HCLTech 02, 2015 - 09, 2016 Lead - Engineer

🧼 тномsом reuters 08, 2010 - 02, 2015 Engineer - Dev

CONTACT

acharshrikanth@gmail.com +91 9535621589

Karnataka, India.

For my portfolio, visit acharshrikanth.github.io

TOOLS

Sketch

Figma

Adobe XD

Photoshop, Krita, GIMP

Adobe Illustrator

Miro, Mural, Confluence

Invision

DOMAINS

Order Management
Business Operations
Banking & Finance
Communication Services
Logistics & Distribution
Health Care

SKILLS

User Research Analysis
Interaction Design
Wireframing & Prototyping
Visual Design & Illustrations
Information Architecture
Usability Testing
Design System
Story Boarding
Coding & Dev. Knowledge
Collaboration & Communication

PROJECTS

Order Management System: Collaborated with the PO's and created UI screens for worlds leading luxury car manufacturers.

Remote work & collaboration: Brainstormed with the team to design the new app for a govt. body of foreign country.

Banking & Finance: Managed project independently, handling requirements and delivering diverse UX design options.

Enterprise Resource Planning: Facilitated client workshops, gained insights of system issues, created elegant UI designs.

Chatbot Assistant: With heuristic evaluation, created intuitive interaction that impressed clients and led to additional projects.

White Paper Document: Created visual diagrams of comprehensive technical white paper document which simplified the complex technical concepts.

Stock Broking Application: Worked for multiple clients on this.

CERTIFICATION

Strategic Insights, Practice, and Impact - RISD (May 2023)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Info. Science - NMAMIT, Nitte. (VTU)